This battle between cis and trans people is not a war that anyone concerned with the liberation of black people should wage.
These moments reek of white supremacy. How do you know it's white supremacy? I'm glad you asked.
The reminder that we don't need white overseers, our physical plantations, when some of us feel obligated to police other people's ways of being, should be evidence enough.
Black people are dying and our rights are being actively eroded. Our issues shouldn't be with trans people, but the systems designed to destroy all of us.
Pay attention. They're working exactly as they're designed to. This cis trans thing ain't our fight.
We should all be united against white supremacy. Gender is a colonial construct.
Different gender and sexual expressions existed in Africa pre-colonialism.
Don't believe me? Look it up! In a book with citations and sources, preferably.
The Spirit of Intimacy, written by Sambufu Sommet, is a brilliant place to start.
I pray sincerely that we all get curious and seek to learn more about sex and gender and the beautifully diverse ways that so many of us come into being,
outside of the toxic ways that white supremacy damages things.
No matter how we enter conversations about social constructs like gender, we should all be asking, what's the goal?
For those defending gender constructs never designed to hold space for the dynamic and diverse ways that we've always...